AURÉLIE JOSSERAND

Multidisciplinary Designer



PROFILE

Over the past ten years, I've built products for companies, businesses and government entities around the globe with a focus on design, usability, accessibility and inclusivity.

While the products I design have been in the built environment, the skills I have learned as an architect and designer are all applicable to experiential design. From working with multi-disciplinary teams, to iterating through design concepts and working with stakeholders, I am committed to meeting client expectations while creating great user experiences.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ARCHITECTURE

University of Oklahoma Oklahoma, 2011-2012

BACHELOR OF ARCHITECTURE

Ecole Nationale Superieure d'Architecture France, 2007-2010

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent French - Native

OTHER QUALIFICATIONS

Registered Architect EDAC Accredited LEED Accredited BD+C

EXPERIENCE

Smithgroup, Washington, District of Columbia

2015 to present - Designer & Architect

- Develops innovative and visually compelling concepts for experiential spaces,
 while considering human-centered design best practices.
- Leads the 3D production process by mentoring peers and implementing the latest trends and innovations in AR, VR and real-time rendering.
- Manages system coordination on large scale projects involving multi-disciplinary teams of engineers and designers.
- Involved in all project phases from early design iterations to project documentation.
- Promotes the company brand through online and in person community activities and organization involvement.

Miles Associates, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

2012 to 2015 - Project Coordinator

- Led 3D visualizations effort by creating compelling digital experiences and identifying software and workflow needs.
- Developed the company Website Design using Squarespace CMS.
- Assisted project teams on crafting design, construction documentation and project pursuits.

AWARDS & LEADERSHIP

Guest Speaker & Workshop Moderator

Howard University, 2024

Lead Panel Moderator

Summer Leadership Summit 2019

Guest Speaker

George Washington University, 2020

Next General Scholar

Summer Leadership Summit 2018

TOOLBOX

Real Time 3D	3DSMAX	HTML5	Human Centered Design
AR/VR	AutoCAD	CSS	Inclusive Design
Adobe Photoshop	Lumion	JavaScript	Project Management
Adobe Illustrator	Sketchup	ReactJS	Web Development
Adobe After Effect	Revit	Mocha	Responsive Design
Adobe Premier Pro	Lidar	Nodes.js	Holistic Design
Figma & XD	Dynamo	GIT	